Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Peter A. Schweitzer Papers, 1916-2005 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings and Speeches (Chronological File), 1978-2005 and undated (Box 19)
  - 1996 (Box 25)
    - Crain Communications lunch (Box 25)
    - Crisis in Audience Research (David Marans) (Box 25)
    - Flint Area Advertising Federation (Steve Brown) (Box 25)
    - Ford Agency-of-Record proposal (Box 25)
    - Ford--Decade of Transformation (Box 25)
    - Ford Global Business Plan (Box 25)
    - Ford presentation to Clive Dodd and A.G. Stanley (Jim Cassidy) (Box 25)
    - Materials for outdoor industry presentation (Box 25)
    - Martin Sorrell WPP presentation (Box 25)
    - Press talk (not delivered) (Box 25)
    - Service recognition awards (Box 25)
    - TAB Great Outdoor Conference (Box 25)
    - U.S. Trade Policies (John Sweetland) (Box 25)
    - Western Michigan Advanced Advertising Students (Box 25)
    - Western Michigan Executive in Residence Program (Box 25)
    - Western Michigan President's Circle Associates (Box 25)
  - 1997 (Box 25)
    - Alliance--Upfront Negotiating Strategy Guidelines (Box 25)
    - Board of Directors Meeting (Box 25)
    - Ford Global Business Unit (Hamish) (Box 26)
    - Ford Global Business Unit Meeting (Box 26)
    - International Federation of Multiple Sclerosis Societies (Box 26)
    - JWT North America (Box 26)
    - JWT Worldwide (Box 26)
    - North American General Managers' Meeting (JWT Chicago) (Box 26)
  - 1998 (Box 26)
    - American Red Cross Everyday Heroes Celebration (Jim Kreiger) (Box 26)
    - Great Britain and Northern Ireland MS Societies (Box 26)
    - Mailboxes, Etc. presentation (Box 26)
    - Niagara Brand Summit (Box 26)
    - Sales and Marketing Executives of Detroit (Box 26)
  - 1999 (Box 26)
    - Automotive News World Conference (Box 26)
    - Board of Directors Meeting, Total Branding Report (Andy Fenning) (Box 26)
    - Brand Communications Strategy and Execution (Peggy Moylan, Don Topping) (Box 26)
    - Edie Goldenberg retirement (Box 26)
    - Lowe's pitch (Box 26)
    - Maritz Business Development Conference (Box 26)
    - Motor Eyes '99 (Michael Graham) (Box 26)
    - World Auto Congress (Box 26)
  - Restricted Materials (Box 26)
    - 2000 (Box 26)
      - Ahead of the Curve (Jwt Detroit Insight Group) (Box 27)
      - CATCH Hall of Fame (Box 27)
      - Chris Jones speech to WPP Board (Box 27)
      - Media and the Work/Family Interface (Cara Descartes, Conrad Kottak) (Box 27)
    - 2000-2001 (Box 27)
      - Service recognition awards (Box 27)
    - 2001 (Box 27)
      - All staff meeting (Box 27)
      - Capturing the Mood of America (David Lamb) (Box 27)
      - Creative Council (Gordon Torr) (Box 27)
      - Florida Global Business Unit Conference (Box 27)
      - Latin America tape (Box 27)
      - The Endless Brand Experience (Box 27)
      - Total Passion presentation (Puerto Rico) (Box 27)
      - WPP Annual Meeting (Box 27)
      - WPP Board presentation (Box 27)
      - WPP Strategy Weekend (Box 27)
    - 2001-2002 (Box 27)
      - Worldwide Executive Group (Box 27)
    - 2002 (Box 27)
      - Berlin management meetings (Box 27)
      - Digital Detroit Conference (Box 27)
      - European Managers Meeting (Box 28)
      - JWT Management Meeting (Box 28)
      - Tokyo speech (Box 28)
      - Western Michigan Advanced Advertising Students (Box 28)
    - 2003 (Box 28)
      - Atlanta Office (Box 28)
      - Automotive News World Conference (Box 28)
      - Detroit staff meeting (Box 28)
      - Ford Global Business Unit (Box 28)
      - Latin American Managers Meeting (Box 28)
      - Thoughts about Transformation (Box 28)
    - 2003-2004 (Box 28)
      - General files (including speeches by others) (Box 28)
    - 2004 (Box 28)
      - Bonita Springs (Box 28)
      - Ford Asia (Box 28)
      - Mazda Global Business Unit (Box 28)
      - ReputationZ (Peter Walshe, Miriam Page) (Box 28)
      - University of Michigan Honors Program (Box 28)
      - University of Michigan, Organizational Studies (Box 28)
    - 2005 (Box 28)
      - Detroit Radio Advertising Group (Box 28)
      - University of Michigan, marketing speech (Box 28)
- Large-Format Materials, 1990-2003 and undated (Box 28)
  - Advertising Age, Ford at 100, 2003 (Box 29)
  - American Profile, Ford Centennial Issue, 2003 June 8-14 (Box 29)
  - American Red Cross, Rhapsody in Red Benefit certificate of appreciation, 1995 (Box 29)
  - Automotive Marketer, Schweitzer feature, 2001 (Box 29)
  - Backup materials for Advertising Research Foundation speech, 1990 (Box 29)
  - Campaign Magazine, The First 100 Years of JWT and Unilever, 1902-2002, 2002 (Box 29)
  - Detroit News and Free Press, The Road Is Ours--Ford Centennial Issue, 2003 May 18 (Box 29)
  - Estima, feature on Boby Coimbra reception (in Spanish), 1994 (Box 29)
  - Ford World, 1996 Jan./Feb. (Box 29)
  - Marketing News, special issue on customer satisfaction (includes Honomichl 50 report), 1990 May 28 (Box 29)
  - Materials for outdoor industry presentation, 1996 (Box 29)
  - Motor City, Ford Centennial Issue, 2003 Mar. 27 (Box 29)
  - Sunday Times, 100 Best Companies to Work for, 2004 (Box 29)
  - Inside JWT Detroit, circa 1997 (Box 30)
  - University of Michigan Volunteer Leadership, 2002 (Box 30)
  - Speech Transparencies (Box 30)
    - Things I've Learned About Global Marketing While Wearing Out Two Passports, undated (Box 31)
    - Detroit Office Update, undated (Box 31)
    - JWT U.S. Board of Directors Meeting, 1994 (Box 31)
    - JWT/Ford organization talk, undated (Box 32)
    - Role of Communication in the New Global Environment, undated (Box 32)
- Audiovisual Materials (Box 32)
  Restrictions on Access: Original audiovisual materials are closed to researchers until use copies can be produced. Please contact Research Services for more information.
  - Originals (Box 32)
    - RL-10079-VHS-0001. Adcrafter speech. 1993. VHS. [Includes Like a Prayer; People comments; DeBeers Infatuation; British Telecom; Kodak Green; Buenos Aires Ford; Health Club Sheena; Mustang Pavillion; Walter Mitty; It Was, It Is Convertible.] (Box 33)
    - RL-10079-VHS-0002. Bob Jeffrey keynote, Brand Leadership Forum. 2001. VHS. (Box 33)
    - RL-10079-VHS-0003. Detroit Chophouse. Undated. VHS. [DTC: Surprise; 3 Stone Ring, 3 spots.] (Box 33)
    - RL-10079-VHS-0004. Detroit Chophouse. Undated. VHS. [Marlboro 1955 and 1970.] (Box 33)
    - RL-10079-VHS-0005. Insight Out: Families in Focus. Undated. VHS. (Box 33)
    - RL-10079-VHS-0006. JWT India new office inauguration. 2002. VHS. (Box 33)
    - RL-10079-VHS-0007. JWT International Selects. 2004. VHS. (Box 33)
    - RL-10079-VHS-0008. Mustang Museum Program Overview. Undated. VHS. (Box 33)
    - RL-10079-VHS-0009. North American Managers Meeting. 2000. VHS. [Includes Thermasilk; Merrill Lynch; Aquafina; Schick Xtreme; Wisk; DeBeers; Kleenex; Lipton Iced Tea; Qwest; Smirnoff Ice; Lipton Brisk.] (Box 33)
    - RL-10079-VHS-0010. Peter Schweitzer comments, MS Society. 2000. VHS. (Box 33)
    - RL-10079-VHS-0011. Untitled. Undated. VHS. (Box 33)
    - RL-10079-VHS-0012. Various spots. Undated. VHS. [Includes Supercuts; Ford F-150; DeBeers; Smarties; Bally.] (Box 33)
    - RL-10079-VHS-0013. WPP annual general meeting. 2003. VHS. [Includes DeBeers; Ford F-150; Foster's; Lubriderm; Kit Kat; Special Olympics; Malibu Rum; Merrill Lynch; Info Center Men's Health.] (Box 33)
    - RL00079-3/4-0001. Burt Manning: The Roots of Communication. 1985. 3/4-inch. [Includes Ernie Kovacs Show; Marty Feldman; Saturday Night Live; Psycho; Sen. McCarthy; The Miracle Worker; Casablanca.] (Box 33)
    - RL00079-3/4-0002. Chris Jones. Undated. 3/4-inch. (Box 33)
    - RL00079-3/4-0003. Rome Conference, Ford 2000/GBU. 1995. 3/4-inch. (Box 33)
    - RL00079-3/4-0004. Sean Fitzpatrick presentation reel; Wall Street Journal Meeting of the Minds. 1991. 3/4-inch. [Includes Chevrolet, Coca-Cola Classic; US Air; Nescafe; Taster's Choice; AT&T; Martini & Rossi; General Motors; Promise Spread; Princess Cruises; Columbia Pictures; Ritz crackers; L'Oreal Preference; Nintendo; Bridgestone Tires; Mennen Speed Stick; Budweiser; Michelob Light; McDonald's.] (Box 33)
    - RL00079-3/4-0005. Tucson presentation. 1996. 3/4-inch. [Includes Like a Prayer; People comments; DeBeers; Kellogg; Kodak Green; Latin American Ford; Mustang; Outdoor designs.] (Box 33)
    - RL00079-3/4-0006. Untitled. Undated. 3/4-inch. [Includes Like a Prayer; People comments; DeBeers Infatuation; British Telecom; Kodak Green; Buenos Aires Ford; Health Club Sheena; Mustang Pavillion; Walter Mitty; It Was, It Is Convertible.] (Box 33)
    - RL00079-CD-0001. HTA storyboard, CNBC. 2002. CD. (Box 33)
    - RL00079-CD-0002. Interview with Peter Schweitzer, Star news, Ipan Public Relations. Undated. CD. (Box 33)
    - RL00079-CD-0003. JWT India new office inauguration. 2002. CD. (Box 33)
    - RL00079-CD-0004. WPP annual general meeting. 2003. CD. [Includes DeBeers; Ford F-150; Foster's; Lubriderm; Kit Kat; Special Olympics; Malibu Rum; Merrill Lynch; Info Center Men's Health.] (Box 33)
    - RL00079-CD-0005. WPP Board; JWT Latin America and Caribbean. 2002. CD. (Box 33)
    - RL00079-DVD-0001. Endless Brand Experience. Undated. DVD. (Box 33)
    - RL00079-DVD-0002. Ford: Welcome to the Next Generation of Ford. 2004. DVD. [Includes Integrated Launch DVD; 2005 Dealer Showroom Loop.] (Box 33)
    - RL00079-DVD-0003. Nestle Innovation Awards. 2005. DVD. (Box 33)
    - RL00079-DVD-0004. Peter Schweitzer, Leaders on Leadership. Detroit Public TV/Wayne State University School of Business Administration. Undated. DVD. (Box 33)
    - RL00079-DVD-0005. Peter Schweitzer, Leaders on Leadership. Detroit Public TV/Wayne State University School of Business Administration. Undated. DVD. (Box 33)
    - RL00079-DVD-0006. Peter Schweitzer, Leaders on Leadership. Detroit Public TV/Wayne State University School of Business Administration. Undated. DVD. (Box 33)
    - RL00079-DVD-0007. University of Michigan undergratuate admissions disc. Undated. DVD. (Box 33)
    - RL00079-CAS-0001. Nasser GBU speech. Undated. Audiocassette. (Box 33)
- Digital Items [Closed] (Box 33)
  Restrictions on Access: Digital materials are closed until reformatting can be accomplished.
  - JWT Puerto Rico. {evolution}. 3.5 disc. DOS format. Undated. (Box 33)
  - JWT Puerto Rico. {evolution}. ZIP disc. DOS format. Undated. (Box 33)
  - JWT San Juan. Total Passion. 3.5 disc. 2001 (Box 33)
  - WPP Strategy Weekend. 3.5 disc. 2001 (Box 33)